## **ERICA INGRAM**

evoingram@aquoco.onmicrosoft.com

- (206) 478-5028
- Seattle, Washington
- in aquocotrans
- evoingram
- www.ericaingram.com

Business professional with a knack for solving real-world problems and overcoming challenges, extremely resourceful and adaptable with excellent communication skills from a decade-long writing career and another decade in court transcription; thorough, self-disciplined, and well equipped to work independently under regular strict deadlines.

## Skills

#### **TECH SKILLS**

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Visual Basic

Git

MySQL

React

Redux

Java

**GSAP** 

Microsoft Access

Adobe XD

**LESS** 

Bootstrap

**Emmet** 

Jest

Formik

**SASS** 

jQuery

Python

PHP

API

UI REST

JSON

#### **LEGAL SERVICES SKILLS**

Legal Research
Editing & Proofreading
Writing
Transcription
Litigation Support
Project Management

## **Employment**

#### Lambda School, Team Lead, Remote

Jan. 2020 to Present

- Code review for every student in my team twice per week
- Hosted two stand-up meetings with six students weekly
- Presentations on various resources to facilitate students' growth during stand-ups
- Mentored & provided feedback to students on improvement areas
- Tracked attendance and other student metrics
- Use of Slackbot & Slack Workflow Builder to manage tasks, information, and reminders

#### A Quo Co., Owner/Operator, Seattle, WA

May 2009 to Present

- Diverse customer base, serving attorneys and pro se parties
- Used text-analyzing software on over 10,000 transcript pages to produce autocorrect entries in Word to improve typing speed/accuracy and automated creation of those entries
- Unique features such as authority hyperlinking via CourtListener, .gov sites as well as tables of authority via VBA automation
- Consistently produced twice the number of transcript pages as most of my colleagues due to VBA automation

## **Projects**

# Transcript Production API Deployed Project

Jan. 2020 to Apr. 2020 Code on GitHub

- Developed using Node, Express, PostgreSQL, and Postman
- 126 endpoints, including contractor & CourtListener, Xero, PayPal,
   & Office API support

### images.nasa.gov search clone Deployed Project

Jan. 2020 to Apr. 2020 Code on GitHub

 React and Redux app clone of the images.nasa.gov library search website

### Prisoner Skills App Deployed Project

Feb. 2020 to Feb. 2020 Code on GitHub

 React and Redux app to help match prisoners with specific skills to potential employers

# Transcription Management Deployed Offline

June 2017 to Jan. 2020 Code on GitHub

- Developed using Visual Basic for Applications, MS Access, and MySQL
- Transcript production workflow management
- Integrated with Office, Acrobat, and WinSCP libraries and several APIs such as CourtListener, Wunderlist, PayPal, OneNote, and others

### Company Website Deployed Project

November 2019 to Jan. 2020 Code on GitHub

- Made with LESS, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Ranks in 90th percentile in Google PageSpeed Insights and first page results for "seattle transcription" in Google, page two for Bing/Duckduckgo

## **Education**

### Lambda School, Remote

Oct. 2019 to Present

Full Stack Web Development and Computer Science

Nine-month computer science and software engineering academy providing intense immersive curriculum in web development and computer science-focused topics such as JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node, React, Redux, Python, Express, Git, SQL, Bootstrap, NPM/Yarn, GSAP, & Jest